Guide to the Caterina Borelli Papers MSS.540
Fales Library and Special Collections
Caterina Borelli Papers
1981-1984
Fales Library and Special Collections
Borelli, Caterina
MSS.540
1 linear foot in 1 record carton
3 audiocassettes
17 Half_Inch_Video_Reel
5 U-matic
The Caterina Borelli Papers consist of audiovisual recordings of performances and interviews of Downtown artists such as Arleen Schloss, Diane Torr, and Steven Durland, as well as Borelli's collaborations with video artists Jean Dupuy and Alex Halkin. As a documentary filmmaker, Borelli lived and worked in New York during the 1970s. Borelli's expansive career includes working in radio, television, and independent film since the early 1980s. During her time in New York, Borelli immersed herself in the performance art scene recording Downtown artists. The collection also includes promotional ephemera of her involvement working with other artists including flyers, a news clipping, and an event poster.
Scope and Contents
The Caterina Borelli Papers consists of audiovisual recordings of performances of Downtown New York City artists such as Arleen Schloss, Diane Torr, and Steven Durland. This collection also contains Borelli's collaborations with Jean Dupuy and Alex Halkin including Male and The Yellow Ribbon Conspiracy. Formats in this collection include 1/2-inch open reel videos, videotapes, audio cassette tapes, and audio reel recordings of Borelli's work and interviews, and documentation of artists' performances. The collection also includes promotional ephemera of her involvement working with other artists including flyers, a newsclipping, and an event poster.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Caterina Borelli (1959- ) is a dual-citizen of Italy and the United States. As a documentary filmmaker, Borelli spent time living and working in New York beginning in 1980. Borelli's expansive career includes working in radio, television, and independent film. During her time in New York, Borelli immersed herself in the performance art scene recording Downtown artists such as Arleen Schloss and Diane Torr. Her work includes experimental video, documentaries, and global news coverage. In addition to her own work, she has also collaborated with video artists such as Jean Dupuy and Alex Halkin. In the advent of the production of the 1/2-inch open reel video, Borelli explored this portable video technology to diversify her work.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Caterina Borelli in November of 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.078.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Fales Library, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596, with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Performance art -- 20th century; Performance art -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions.; Alternative spaces (Arts facilities); Documentary films -- United States.; Schloss, Arleen; Torr, Diane
- Performance article, and flyers, 1980s; cuid28641 (Box 1)
- Interviews with Robert and Sandro, circa 1980; cuid28643 (Box 1, Audiocassette cuid28643)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Duration: 95 minutes
- Robert and Joey, circa 1980; cuid28644 (Box 1, Audiocassette cuid28644)
  Duration: 47 minutes
- Grey and Sandro, circa 1980; cuid28645 (Box 1, Audiocassette cuid28645)
  Duration: 88 minutes; Preservation note: "Audio is in right-channel only; re-mixed to both channels for access copy"
- Male by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin, 1981; cuid28646 (Box 1)
- Male by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin, 1981; cuid28647 (Box 1)
- Male by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin, 1981; cuid28648 (Box 1)
- Male by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin, 1981; cuid28649 (Box 1)
- Male by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin [Belize], 1981; cuid28663 (Box 1)
- The Yellow Ribbon Conspiracy by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin -- Performances by Diane Torr, Alex Halkin, and Caterina Borelli, 1981-01; cuid28660 (Box 1)
  Format: EIAJ-1; Duration: 33 minutes; Preservation note: Distorted audio at 21-25 minutes.
- The Yellow Ribbon Conspiracy by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin -- Performances by Diane Torr, Jose Pedro Varela, Grey, January, 1981; cuid28661 (Box 1)
  Format: EIAJ-1; Duration: 33 minutes; Preservation note: Long blank section at end followed by short recording, captured separately.
- The Yellow Ribbon Conspiracy by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin, 1981-01; cuid28656 (Box 1)
- The Yellow Ribbon Conspiracy by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin -- Ostages Parade, 1981-01-30; cuid28659 (Box 1)
- Arleen Schloss Performing [Tape 1], 1981-01-31; cuid28657 (Box 1)
- Arleen Schloss Performing [Tape 2], 1981-01-31; cuid28658 (Box 1)
- A's Carole Bovoso, David J. Simon Null Set -- Public Servants [Tape 1], 1981-03-11; cuid28664 (Box 1)
- A's [Tape 2] [No Sound], 1981-03-11; cuid28665 (Box 1)
- Roast Pork and Bean Curd on Rice a performance by Steven Durland at A's, 1981-03-18; cuid28666 (Box 1)
- Confessions Under Luna by Jean Dupuy and Malesian Dancer at A's Space, 1981-03-25; cuid28662 (Box 1)
- Confessions Under Luna by Jean Dupuy at A's Space, 1981-03-25; cuid28653 (Box 1)
  Master
- Confessions Under Luna by Jean Dupuy at A's Space, 1981-03-25; cuid28654 (Box 1)
- Arleen Schloss at Green Space, 1981-05-08; cuid28652 (Box 1)
- Arleen Schloss at Green Space, 1981-05-08; cuid28642 (Box 1)
- Visual Materials for Arleen Schloss Performance at Greene Space, 1981-05-08; cuid28651 (Box 1)
- Male by Caterina Borelli and Alex Halkin, 1981-05-31; cuid28655 (Box 1)
- The Terminal Show, 1984; cuid28650 (Box 1)
- Performance Poster, Circa 1980s; cuid28667 (Flat-file-folder 13)